Education and Training
Bachelor of Science Electrical Equipment Installation And Repair Knox College , City July 1993
OPERATIONS MANAGER
Summary

High-performing Operation Manager with over 20 years of experience delivering successful improvements for business operations, profitability and team development. Resourceful project manager and compliance specialist to thrive in fast-paced and changing environments. Dedicated to sustaining operational accuracy and delivering results for optimal profitability.

#### Skills

- Workforce training
- Cost reduction and containment
- Contract review and recommendations
- Project management
- Cost reduction strategies
- Dedicated
- Warehouse operations
- Staff retention
- · Conflict mediation
- Maintenance planning
- Health and safety compliance
- Multi-site operations
- Project management abilities
- Incidents management

### Experience

Operations Manager

Papa John's | Bethel Park, PA | February 2019 - December 2021

- Directed day-to-day operations by spearheading implementation of short-term and long-term strategies to achieve business plan and profitability goals.
- Conducted performance reviews providing coaching and feedback to benefit both company and employee.
- · Managed company operations with responsibility for profit and loss, scheduling, training and inventory control.
- Implemented policies and standard operating procedures and managed quality, customer service and logistics.
- Collaborated with staff to maximize customer satisfaction, streamline procedures and improve bottom-line profitability.
- Planned daily operational strategies, including delivery routing, team workflows and promotional initiatives.
- Delivered positive customer experiences by implementing effective quality assurance practices.
- Maintained safety and emergency readiness among personnel by disseminating information on and monitoring compliance with regulatory and organizational policies.
- Improved morale and management communication by creating employee recognition and rewards practices.
- Recruited, hired and trained crew members on application of projects, customer relations and customer service.

## Maintenance Mechanic

Johns Manville Corp | Macon , GA | March 2017 - January 2019

- Installed, repaired and maintained equipment.
- Operated hand and power tools to complete repairs.
- Repaired and replaced worn and defective parts.
- Tested machine malfunctions and performed repairs.
- Inspected machines before and after use to verify optimal performance.
- Adjusted and calibrated machines as required.
- Studied repair and use manuals to ensure correct maintenance.
- Ran regular tests on machines and fixed early problems.
- Employed best maintenance and safety practices with minimal complaints, incidents or lost-time accidents.
- Diagnosed and repaired mechanical issues according to industry standards.
- Maintained compliance with internal and regulatory safety standards.
- Diagnosed equipment malfunctions and completed repairs to restore equipment and maintain uptime.
- Provided top quality control to eliminate maintenance downtime.

# Operations Manager

Papa John's | Billings, MT | July 2002 - February 2017

- Managed company operations with responsibility for profit and loss, scheduling, training and inventory control.
- Implemented policies and standard operating procedures and managed quality, customer service and logistics.
- Delivered positive customer experiences by implementing effective quality assurance practices.

- Collaborated with staff to maximize customer satisfaction, streamline procedures and improve bottom-line profitability.
- Planned daily operational strategies, including delivery routing, team workflows and promotional initiatives.
- Maintained safety and emergency readiness among personnel by disseminating information on and monitoring compliance with regulatory and organizational policies.
- Improved morale and management communication by creating employee recognition and rewards practices.
- Recruited, hired and trained crew members on application of projects, customer relations and customer service.
- Developed initiatives for process improvement and reviewed and assessed ongoing operations.
- Oversaw financial management, budget management, accounting and payroll activities.
- Reviewed daily financial reports and reconciled accounts to keep information current and accurate.
- Built upon established practice standards to improve operational performance and reduce labor costs.
- Enforced security policies and procedures to protect company assets from theft, loss or damage.

### Supervisor

Magnolia Bakery | Los Angeles, CA | July 1994 - February 2017

- Resolved customer complaints and adjusted policies to meet changing needs.
- Established and enforced clear goals to keep employees working collaboratively.
- Provided ongoing training to address staff needs.
- Complied with company policies, objectives and communication goals.
- Identified and corrected performance and personnel issues to reduce impact to business operations.
- Maintained operating schedules to provide effective coverage for key areas and achieve objectives.
- Coached and mentored 34 staff members through constructive feedback to develop long-term career goals.
- Interviewed applicants, recommended individuals for hiring and evaluated staff performance.
- Realigned workflows with changing business demands by evaluating processes and employee strengths.
- Promoted high customer satisfaction by resolving problems with knowledgeable and friendly service.
- Remained calm and professional in stressful circumstances and when dealing with unhappy customers, effectively diffusing situations.
- Treated associates with fairness and respect, providing recognition of accomplishments.